#### Contact

susankelly129@comcast.net

www.linkedin.com/in/susan-kelly-edd-rn-cmsrn-cne-chse-b9472116 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Nursing

Nursing Education

Healthcare

### Certifications

Certified Nurse Educator (CNE)
Certified Medical-Surgical
Registered Nurse (CMSRN)
Certified Healthcare Simulation
Educator (CHSE)

# Susan Kelly, EdD, RN, CMSRN, CNE, CHSE

Highly Motivated Nurse Educator

Carnegie, Pennsylvania

### Summary

I am a highly motivated nurse educator with expertise in teaching, mentoring and tutoring undergraduate and graduate students. I use simulation and other methods of instruction to teach and work with students to help them succeed on preparation for NCLEX.

## Experience

**Duquesne University** 

5 years

Director of Undergraduate Adjunct Faculty and Clinical Affairs July 2019 - Present (1 year)

Oversees the clinical education aspects for the undergraduate program. The position is responsible for effectively recruiting, hiring, orientating and evaluating adjunct faculty, as well as, for the overall quality of the clinical education with respect to securing clinical sites, adjunct faculty performance, site placement and compliance with affiliation agreements.

Clinical Assistant Professor 2015 - Present (5 years)

Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania

Teaching students in undergraduate education in a variety of role. Area of specialty includes preparation for standardized testing and the NCLEX exam. Teach undergraduate and second degree accelerated nursing students in Pathophysiology and Medical Surgical Nursing using a variety of instructional methods. Develop various evaluation methods and curriculum to acclimate students to the nursing profession. Assist adjunct faculty in their role as a clinical instructor. Currently serve on the Simulation Task Force for the school of nursing to design effective high-fidelity simulation to be used across the nursing curriculum.

UPMC Presbyterian
Staff Nurse -- Admission Team

December 2012 - November 2015 (3 years)

University of Pittsburgh School of Nursing 5 years 4 months

Assistant Professor September 2014 - April 2015 (8 months)

Primary Teacher for clinical in the senior level of the undergraduate nursing program. Responsibilities include but are not limited to working with the primary teacher of the didactic portion on content and working with instructors teaching in the course. Coordinated part-time instructors for clinical rotation and worked with teaching assistants in evaluation of students,

Clinical Instructor
January 2010 - September 2014 (4 years 9 months)

Clinical Instructor to students in the Acute and Tertiary Department. Students include sophmore level and senior level in an acute care setting. Teach both 2nd degree (Accelerated BSN) students and traditional students. Also manage students in their leadership/transitions in their senior level. Work to develop plan of care of complex post surgical patients and assist the students in developing new skills such as medication administration, managing patient assignments and develop critical thinking skills. Evaluate and document their development throughout the semester. Assist in the Clinical lab setting on skills and physical assessment. Also instruct didactic specifically in neurological disorders, heart failure, hypertension, and stroke.

Waynesburg University
Facilitator, Adjunct Faculty
November 2009 - September 2014 (4 years 11 months)

Community College of Allegheny County Adjunct Nursing Faculty January 2007 - December 2012 (6 years)

Hospira Worldwide, Inc.
Clinical Nurse Consultant/MMS Specialist
April 2004 - October 2009 (5 years 7 months)

Abbott
Clinical Nurse Consultant
June 2001 - April 2004 (2 years 11 months)

## Education

University of Pittsburgh School of Education EdD, Doctor of Education · (2010 - 2014)

Robert Morris University
MSN, Nursing Education · (2006 - 2008)

Duquesne University
MS, Leadership & Business Ethics · (2003 - 2005)

University of Pittsburgh BSN, Nursing · (1998 - 1999)

Ohio Valley School of Nursing Diploma, Nursing · (1993 - 1995)